ANNA SYRIGONAKI

Barcelona, Spain • +34600906360 • a.sirigonaki@gmail.com • linkedin.com/in/anna-syrigonaki • https://github.com/AnnaSyr1

Sales and Marketing Lead

Experienced Marketing and Sales leader with 6+ years in digital marketing, team management, and stakeholder engagement. Recognized for exceptional leadership and coaching. Implemented BETA campaign formats, leading to a 35% improvement in product adoption rate. Demonstrated ability to deliver impactful results in a fastpaced environment.

WORK EXPERIENCE

Sales Team Leader • Barcelona

07/2022 - 06/2024

Google Inc.

powered by Teleperformance Spain S.L.

- Led a team of 15 Account Strategists, optimizing integrated marketing campaigns in Google Ads and boosting consumer engagement and conversion rates.
- Impemented and tested new BETA campaign formats (DemandGen, Pmax for travel goals) with specific advertisers that led to a 35% improvement in product adoption rate and provided data insights for future implementations
- Improved client services and business growth through effective internal and external Stakeholder Management strategies.
- Recognized for exceptional leadership and team coaching for Q4 2023 among 53 teams.
- Achieved Performance Target for 6 Consecutive Quarters: (123 Q1 2023, 118 Q2 2023, 105 Q3 2023, 129 Q4 2023, 107 O1 2024, 106 O2 2024) resulting in remarkable sales achievements.

Agency Account Strategist • Barcelona Google Inc.

09/2020 - 06/2022

- Managed and optimized a 15% increase in quarterly ad spend while establishing strong relationships with the top 3% Advertising Agencies in Greece.
- Optimized cross-channel campaigns (Search, Display, Video) and campaign budgets to drive customer retention and business goals.
- Exceeded product adoption Targets for 7 Quarters: (136 Q4-2020, 120 Q1-2021, 115 Q2-2021, 105 Q3-2021, 130 Q1 2022, 125 Q2-2022, 140 Q3 2022).
- Won the Best Practices competitions in Q1 2021 & Q2 2022 for excellent campaign performance.

Marketing Operations Specialist • Heraklion, Greece VSCOPE Agency S.A.

01/2019 - 09/2020

- Develop and execute B2B advertising campaigns on Google Ads and LinkedIn Ads for 40 accounts.
- Created comprehensive campaign strategies leveraging multiple channels, conducted risk assessments, and developed contingency plans, contributing to 25% increase in sales and overall campaign success in the hospitality sector.
- Aligned and coordinated cross-functional teams and the creative production team to meet campaign goals

Marketing Assistant Intern • Valencia, Spain Sheetgo S.L.

07/2018 - 01/2019

 Mapped and optimized the complete consumer journey, resulting in a 15% increase in conversion rate and a 10% decrease in customer acquisition cost, leading to improved campaign effectiveness and cost-efficiency.

Marketing Assistant Intern • Heraklion, Greece

03/2018 - 06/2018

Aquila Atlantis Hotel

 Collaborated with external creative production teams to deliver high-quality assets on time for Paid and Social Media and Email campaigns, leading to a 30% surge in customer loyalty and awareness

EDUCATION

Data Analytics Certification

Big Blue Data Analytics Academy

01/2024 - 06/2024

A bootcamp course of 280 hours immersive hands-on training. Subjets covered: **Python programming language** (Pandas, NumPy, JSON) **No-SQL & SQL Databases**, Advanced Cleaning, Explanatory Data Analytics, Webscrapping, APIs, **Customer and Market Analysis**. Data Visualization tool: **PowerBI**

Business Administration

Hellenic Mediterranean University

09/2013 - 08/2017

Erasmus+ studies in Czech University of Life Sciences in Prague

Thesis: Primary Research of Advertising methods of Hotels in Heraklion

PROJECTS

PowerBI Dashboard

Big Blue Data Analytics Academy

Analyzed a big amount of salaries data for the sector of Data Analysts worldwide with Python and created a guide for Job Seekers in a PowerBI Interactive Dashboard. GitHub link.

Marketing Campaign Effectiveness Report

Big Blue Data Analytics Academy

Analyzed in Python a dataset of Marketing Campaigns' Performance, created dashboards in PowerBI and a presentation to depict the insights and recommendations to improve campaigns' effectiveness. GitHub Page

Explanatory Data Analytics Project

Big Blue Data Analytics Academy

Analyzed a sales dataset of the ABC Bank in Python to provide insights revenue, sales operations, and customer loyalty. Recommended actions to develop Sales Enablement and Sales Process. GitHub link

VOLUNTEERING & LEADERSHIP

Erasmus Student Network Greece

09/2016 - 07/2020

Board Member

Elected President of my University for 2 mandates. Elected as National Representative of the Greek Universities to play a strategic direction role in the Erasmus+ future. Elected Event Manager of the international conference called "CNR Crete 2018" and "The Crete Trip 2018 & 2019"

TEDxUniversityofCrete

01/2018 - 01/2020

Organizer

SKILLS

Soft Skills: Adaptability, Attention to detail, Coaching, Data-Driven Strategies, Effective Communication, Leadership, Self-Motivation, Stakeholder Management, Strategic Thinking, Team Development

Hard Skills: Agile Project Management, CRM Data Accuracy, Customer Analysis, Data Analysis, Data Visualization, GONG, Google Ads, Google Analytics 4, Google Tag Manager, LinkedIn Ads, Market Analysis, Marketing Automation Tools, Meta Ads, PowerBI, Python, Reports and Dashboards, Search Engine Marketing, Web Scraping

Languages: English, Greek, Spanish